你大声说出来了吗？不是在心里说，而是真的出声。
Did you say it out loud? Not to yourself, actually out loud. If you did, go on to
如果没有，让我们谈谈你为什么没有。
the next exercise. If not, let's talk about why you didn't. As we all know,
固执是负面词，没有人愿意把负面词加在
stubborn is a negative word and nobody wants to attribute a negative word to
自己身上。正如著名怪脾气人物 Bertrand Russell 所说：
himself or herself. As the famous curmudgeon Bertrand Russell said, I'm
我是坚定，你是固执，他是死脑筋。很有意思的是，固执
firm. You are obstinate. He is a pig-headed fool. Interestingly, stubbornness
既有积极的一面：稳定、可靠、持久；也有消极的一面：固执、
has both positive, consistent, reliable, persistent, negative, stubborn,
回想一下人生中某个坚持终于得到回报的时刻，
inflexible, rigid aspects. Think back in your life to a time when persistence paid
那可能是把一个想法坚持到底，并成功实现，
off. It may have been following through on an idea to successful fruition or
为对你重要的事情克服看似无法克服的困难。
overcoming apparently insurmountable odds on something important to you. Own that.
这是你的经历。我最喜欢的回答之一，是我问一位成功商人：
It's yours. One of my favorite responses was when I asked a successful businessman
是否一切都有人交到他手上、创业是否很容易、或者
if he'd had everything handed to him, if building his business had been easy, or if
是否必须奋战才能成功。“奋战？”他厉声说，“我简直是拼命！”
he'd had to fight to succeed. Fight? He barked. I've had to kill! Now, however,
我们要看看固执是如何阻碍你的道路。
we're going to look at how stubbornness can get in your way. Stubbornness isn't
未必只是人生后期才出现的东西，也常常是一种天生特质。
necessarily something that just happens later in life, but is often an innate
我们许多人对什么是正确有根深蒂固的感觉，也很难违背。
trait. Many of us have a deep-seated feeling of what is right, and it's hard to
如果你是视觉型学习者，拼写测试往往做得不错。
go against this. If you're a visual learner, chances are you did well on
因此，你会觉得拼写有一套正确形式。
spelling tests, and so you have a sense of the rightness of spelling. It can be
拼写可以被检查和验证。然而，口语对你来说可能显得非常流动、自由。
checked and validated. Speech, however, may seem very fluid and free-form to you.
不过，要完成这个训练过程，你需要接受：音标拼写对口语是正确的。
For this process, however, you need to embrace the rightness of phonetic spelling
这和书面英语拼写的正确性一样重要。
for speech as much as you embrace the rightness of spelling for written English
也和数字的数学记法一样。有时你并不是固执。
and the rightness of mathematical notation for numbers. Sometimes you're not being
你确实会忘记，因为你关注的是自己在说什么，
stubborn. You really do forget because you're focusing on what you're saying
为了说明这一点，一位研究人员做过一个
instead of how you're saying it. To illustrate this, a researcher had a
实验室冷藏设备的门出了问题，那个又高又竖的
problem with the door of his lab refrigeration unit, whose tall upright
把手松了。他没时间修，就决定通过拉
handle had come loose. Not having time to fix it, he decided to open it by pulling
侧面去开。几分钟后，他回来拿更多小瓶，
on the side. minutes later, he went back to grab some more vials and opened the
用把手打开冰箱，结果把手完全松脱，砰地砸到他头上。哎哟！
fridge with the handle. It came completely loose and clunked him on the head. Ow!
这一次，他知道自己必须记住，于是把一张纸条直接贴在把手上，
This time, he knew he had to remember, so he put a note right on the handle to
再一次，几分钟后，当他回去找另一个
remind himself. And again, a few minutes later, when he went back to get another
小瓶时，他抓住把手，又撞到了自己的头。哎哟！显然，
vial, he grabbed the handle and hit himself on the head again. Ow! Clearly, he
他需要一个更显眼的办法。于是他拿出整整一版报纸，盖住了
needed a more dramatic solution. He took a whole page of newspaper and covered the
整个冰箱把手都盖住，这样下次他无意识地去抓
entire handle of the fridge so that the next time he mindlessly grabbed the
把手时，报纸发出声响，他才意识到自己正要做什么。
handle, the newspaper crackled, and he realized what he was about to do. It's not
并不是他想被砸到头，只是他一直忘记，因为他
like he wanted to get hit in the head, he just kept forgetting because he was
专注于目标而不是过程。
focused on the goal and not the process. Sometimes people speaking English are so
有时，说英语的人太专注于对话中用词的最终结果，
focused on the end product of using words in conversation, like he was in the end
就像他只想着从冰箱里取出小瓶这个最终结果一样，以至于忘了把
product of getting vials out of the fridge, that they forget to include the
口音和发音纳入过程。
accent and pronunciation.